<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on Yasunori SAWAKI</title>
    <link>https://yasuit21.github.io/en/categories/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on Yasunori SAWAKI</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ja-jp</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 00:15:44 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yasuit21.github.io/en/categories/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New Co-authored Paper Published in EPS!</title>
      <link>https://yasuit21.github.io/en/news/2025/07/0031/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 00:15:44 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yasuit21.github.io/en/news/2025/07/0031/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We published a new paper in Earth, Planets and Space about the aftershock distribution of the Mj7.6 Noto Peninsula earthquake on 1 January 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This earthquake triggered extensive aftershocks. Previously, offshore aftershock locations were poorly constrained due to simplified velocity models. Our study used a 3D velocity model and Markov chain Monte Carlo to precisely determine hypocenters. Results show aftershocks occurred at 15 km depth or shallower, indicating the main rupture involved shallow submarine faults, contributing to tsunami generation. The aftershock distribution significantly differs from previous seismicity, suggesting a complex fault network across the peninsula influenced the Mj7.6 earthquake and subsequent activity, as suggested in 

&lt;a href=&#34;https://yasuit21.github.io/ja/news/2025/04/0027/&#34;&gt;Sawaki et al. (2025)&lt;/a&gt;

.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check the paper below for details!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shiina, T., H. Horikawa, &lt;strong&gt;Y. Sawaki&lt;/strong&gt;, K. Sagae, and K. Imanishi (2025). Aftershock distribution of the 2024 Noto Peninsula Earthquake, Japan, determined using a 3D velocity structure and uncertainty quantification. &lt;em&gt;Earth, Planets and Space&lt;/em&gt;, 77, 94. 

&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1186/s40623-025-02227-4&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1186/s40623-025-02227-4&lt;/a&gt;

 (Open Access)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New preprint</title>
      <link>https://yasuit21.github.io/en/news/2025/05/0029/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 11:04:44 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yasuit21.github.io/en/news/2025/05/0029/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have posted a new preprint on the fault geometry for the Mw 5.0 western Kanagawa earthquake in eastern Japan on 9 August 2024. This is a preprint (peer-review not completed), but feel free to check it out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sawaki, Y.&lt;/strong&gt;, T. Shiina, and T. Uchide. Intraslab reverse faulting adjacent to the hypocenter of the 1923 Kanto earthquake: The Mw 5.0 western Kanagawa earthquake in eastern Japan on 9 August 2024 [Preprint v1]. &lt;em&gt;Research Square&lt;/em&gt;. 

&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-6353744/v1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-6353744/v1&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our New Paper in JGR Solid Earth!</title>
      <link>https://yasuit21.github.io/en/news/2025/04/0027/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 20:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yasuit21.github.io/en/news/2025/04/0027/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have estimated the fault geometry of the 2024 Noto Peninsula Earthquake in central Japan on 1 January 2024. Our analysis reveals major and minor fault planes aligned along the coastline beneath the peninsula. Notably, we identified a more counter-clockwise rotated plane in eastern Wajima and an east-dipping plane along the west coast. These localized structural complexities suggest intricate fault slip behavior and exhibit a strong correlation with gravity anomalies and geological structures. This research contributes to a deeper understanding of the formation and seismotectonics of the Noto Peninsula.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also won the &lt;strong&gt;AIST President Award 2024&lt;/strong&gt; related to 

&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aist.go.jp/aist_j/aist_award/2024/apa.html#s1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;Contribution to National Earthquake Disaster Prevention Measures: Response to the 2024 Noto Peninsula Earthquake&lt;/a&gt;

 (in Japanese)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check the paper and software below!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sawaki, Y.&lt;/strong&gt;, T. Shiina, K. Sagae, Y. Sato, H. Horikawa, A. Miyakawa, K. Imanishi, and T. Uchide (2025). Fault Geometries of the 2024 Mw 7.5 Noto Peninsula Earthquake from Hypocenter-Based Hierarchical Clustering of Point-Cloud Normal Vectors. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Geophysical Research: Solid Earth&lt;/em&gt;, 130, e2024JB030233. 

&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2024JB030233&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1029/2024JB030233&lt;/a&gt;

 (Open Access)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sawaki, Y.&lt;/strong&gt;, Y. Sato, and T. Uchide (2025). FaultNVC: Earthquake Fault Plane Extractor through Point-Cloud Normal Vector Clustering for Hypocenter Distributions [Software]. &lt;em&gt;Open-File Report of Geological Survey of Japan, AIST&lt;/em&gt;, no. 759. 

&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gsj.jp/publications/pub/openfile/openfile0759.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;https://www.gsj.jp/publications/pub/openfile/openfile0759.html&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our New Paper Published!</title>
      <link>https://yasuit21.github.io/en/news/2024/10/0022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 16:35:47 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yasuit21.github.io/en/news/2024/10/0022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We imaged the slab and crustal structure of the Kii Peninsula in the Nankai subduction zone in SW Japan using a receiver-function-like analysis. Positive impedance contrasts in the forearc crust correspond to the top surface or inside &lt;strong&gt;Kumano pluton&lt;/strong&gt;, which may control fluid conditions around slow-earthquake sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check it out below!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sawaki, Y.&lt;/strong&gt;, Y. Ito, E. S. M. Garcia, A. Miyakawa, and T. Shibutani (2024). Deep plutonic bodies over low-frequency earthquakes revealed from receiver-side Green&amp;rsquo;s functions. &lt;em&gt;Tectonophysics&lt;/em&gt;, 892, 230536. 

&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tecto.2024.230536&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1016/j.tecto.2024.230536&lt;/a&gt;

 (Open Access)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New preprint alert!</title>
      <link>https://yasuit21.github.io/en/news/2024/04/0020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 14:06:06 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yasuit21.github.io/en/news/2024/04/0020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have a new preprint on the seismic structure beneath the Kii Peninsula, southwestern Japan, available on SSRN. While it&amp;rsquo;s not yet peer-reviewed, feel free to check it out if you&amp;rsquo;re interested!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sawaki, Y.&lt;/strong&gt;, Y. Ito, E. S. M. Garcia, A. Miyakawa, and T. Shibutani. Deep Plutonic Bodies Over Low-Frequency Earthquakes Revealed from Receiver-Side Green&amp;rsquo;s Functions. Available at SSRN: 

&lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4793654&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;http://dx.doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4793654&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
