<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hypocenter on Yasunori SAWAKI</title>
    <link>https://yasuit21.github.io/en/tags/hypocenter/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hypocenter on Yasunori SAWAKI</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ja-jp</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 20:00:00 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yasuit21.github.io/en/tags/hypocenter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Our New Paper in JGR Solid Earth!</title>
      <link>https://yasuit21.github.io/en/news/2025/04/0027/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 20:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yasuit21.github.io/en/news/2025/04/0027/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have estimated the fault geometry of the 2024 Noto Peninsula Earthquake in central Japan on 1 January 2024. Our analysis reveals major and minor fault planes aligned along the coastline beneath the peninsula. Notably, we identified a more counter-clockwise rotated plane in eastern Wajima and an east-dipping plane along the west coast. These localized structural complexities suggest intricate fault slip behavior and exhibit a strong correlation with gravity anomalies and geological structures. This research contributes to a deeper understanding of the formation and seismotectonics of the Noto Peninsula.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check the paper and software below!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sawaki, Y.&lt;/strong&gt;, T. Shiina, K. Sagae, Y. Sato, H. Horikawa, A. Miyakawa, K. Imanishi, and T. Uchide (2025). Fault Geometries of the 2024 Mw 7.5 Noto Peninsula Earthquake from Hypocenter-Based Hierarchical Clustering of Point-Cloud Normal Vectors. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Geophysical Research: Solid Earth&lt;/em&gt;, 130, e2024JB030233. 

&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2024JB030233&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1029/2024JB030233&lt;/a&gt;

 (Open Access)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sawaki, Y.&lt;/strong&gt;, Y. Sato, and T. Uchide (2025). FaultNVC: Earthquake Fault Plane Extractor through Point-Cloud Normal Vector Clustering for Hypocenter Distributions [Software]. &lt;em&gt;Open-File Report of Geological Survey of Japan, AIST&lt;/em&gt;, no. 759. 

&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gsj.jp/publications/pub/openfile/openfile0759.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;https://www.gsj.jp/publications/pub/openfile/openfile0759.html&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
